(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-21T16:52:12.390656",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Shout in Crisis SPECIAL ITEMS
hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP
"Shout in Crisis" Penlightをお持ちのお客様へ
To owners of the "Shout in Crisis" Penlight
Hoshimachi Suisei 2nd Solo Live "Shout in Crisis" 開演までしばらくお待ちください
Hoshimachi Suisei 2nd Solo Live "Shout in Crisis" - Please wait a moment until the opening
ESSENTIALS PACK BLACK ver. ¥11,000
ESSENTIALS PACK LIGHT BLUE ver. ¥11,000
Shout in Crisis SPECIAL ITEMS
hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP
"Shout in Crisis" Penlightをお持ちのお客様へ
To owners of the "Shout in Crisis" Penlight
Hoshimachi Suisei 2nd Solo Live "Shout in Crisis" 開演までしばらくお待ちください
Hoshimachi Suisei 2nd Solo Live "Shout in Crisis" - Please wait a moment until the opening
ESSENTIALS PACK BLACK ver. ¥11,000
ESSENTIALS PACK LIGHT BLUE ver. ¥11,000
Shout in Crisis SPECIAL ITEMS
hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP
"Shout in Crisis" Penlightをお持ちのお客様へ
To owners of the "Shout in Crisis" Penlight
Hoshimachi Suisei 2nd Solo Live "Shout in Crisis" 開演までしばらくお待ちください
Hoshimachi Suisei 2nd Solo Live "Shout in Crisis" - Please wait a moment until the opening
ESSENTIALS PACK BLACK ver. ¥11,000
ESSENTIALS PACK LIGHT BLUE ver. ¥11,000
Shout in Crisis SPECIAL ITEMS
hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP
"Shout in Crisis" Penlightをお持ちのお客様へ
To owners of the "Shout in Crisis" Penlight
Hoshimachi Suisei 2nd Solo Live "Shout in Crisis" 開演までしばらくお待ちください
Hoshimachi Suisei 2nd Solo Live "Shout in Crisis" - Please wait a moment until the opening
ESSENTIALS PACK BLACK ver. ¥11,000
ESSENTIALS PACK LIGHT BLUE ver. ¥11,000
Shout in Crisis SPECIAL ITEMS
hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP
オールスターカードゲーム リバース！
All-star card game Reバース!
ホロライブの豪華メンバーがカードゲームの舞台に再び！
The gorgeous members of Hololive return to the card game stage!
一緒にきらめきを感じよう！
Let's feel the sparkle together!
ブースターパックプラス ホロライブプロダクション Vol.2 2月10日金曜発売
Booster Pack Plus: hololive production Vol.2 - Released Friday, February 10th!
ヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Weiss Schwarz!
ホロライブプロダクションが、またまたカードに大集合！
Hololive production gathers on cards once again!
広がるヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Weiss Schwarz is expanding!
ブースターパック ホロライブプロダクション Vol.2
Booster Pack: hololive production Vol.2
3月24日(金)発売！
Released Friday, March 24th!
ブシロード！
Bushiroad!
新しい生活様式で楽しもう！
Enjoy with the new lifestyle!
みるハコ！
Miruhaco!
ライブやフェスに行きたいな〜
I want to go to concerts and festivals...
だったらみるハコ！
Then Miruhaco!
大音量のライブビューイングが思いっきり楽しめる！
Enjoy high-volume live viewings to the fullest!
映画を大きい画面で見たいな〜
I want to watch movies on a big screen...
だったらみるハコ！
Then Miruhaco!
大画面のモニターで映画やアニメを楽しもう！
Enjoy movies and anime on a large screen monitor!
みるハコなら、カラオケボックスで
With Miruhaco, in a karaoke box
音楽ライブや映画が楽しめる！ライブビューイングも！
enjoy music lives and movies! Live viewings too!
お近くのジョイサウンドで、みるハコ！
At your nearest JOYSOUND, Miruhaco!
グッズはですね、全部で8種類。
There are eight types of merchandise in total.
ペンライトはですね、点灯時……
As for the penlight, when turned on...
オールスターカードゲーム リバース！
All-Star Card Game Reバース!
ホロライブの豪華メンバーがカードゲームの舞台に再び！
The all-star members of Hololive return to the card game stage!
一緒にときめきを感じよう！
Let's experience the excitement together!
ブースターパックプラス ホロライブプロダクション Vol.2 2月10日(金)発売！
Booster Pack Plus Hololive Production Vol.2 releases on Friday, February 10!
ブシロード
Bushiroad
ヴァイスシュヴァルツ
Weiß Schwarz
ホロライブプロダクションが、またまたカードに大集合！
Hololive Production is gathering in cards once again!
広がるヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Expanding Weiß Schwarz!
ブースターパック ホロライブプロダクション Vol.2
Booster Pack Hololive Production Vol.2
ブシロード
Bushiroad
みるハコ
Miruhako
新しい生活様式で楽しもう！
Enjoy with the new lifestyle!
ライブやフェスに行きたいな～
I want to go to live concerts and festivals~
だったらみるハコ！
Then use Miruhako!
大音量のライブビューイングが思いっきり楽しめる！
You can fully enjoy high-volume live viewing!
映画を大きい画面で見たいな～
I want to watch movies on a big screen~
だったらみるハコ！
Then use Miruhako!
大画面のモニターで映画やアニメを楽しもう！
Enjoy movies and anime on a large screen monitor!
みるハコなら、カラオケボックスで音楽ライブや映画が楽しめる、ライブビューイングも！
With Miruhako, you can enjoy music live performances and movies in a karaoke box, even live viewing!
お近くのジョイサウンドで！
At your nearby JOYSOUND!
本日は、星街すいせいセカンドソロライブ「Shout in Crisis」にご来場をいただきまして、誠にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for attending Hoshimachi Suisei's 2nd Solo Live "Shout in Crisis" today.
開演に先立ちまして、お客様にご注意並びにご案内を申し上げます。
Prior to the start of the performance, we would like to make some notices and announcements to our customers.
本日の撮影・録音、録画器材の使用は固くお断りいたします。
Photography, sound recording, and video recording equipment are strictly prohibited today.
館内は禁煙となっております。
Smoking is prohibited inside the venue.
喫煙はご遠慮下さいますようお願い申し上げます。
Please refrain from smoking.
また、本公演は避難誘導等の消灯を行います。
Also, during this performance, lights will be turned off for evacuation guidance.
万が一避難が必要になった場合はすぐに非常灯を点灯しますので、係員の指示に従っていただきますようお願いいたします。
In the unlikely event of an evacuation, emergency lights will turn on immediately; please follow staff instructions.
新型コロナウイルス感染拡大防止対策として、マスクの着用、手指の消毒、ソーシャルディスタンスのご協力をお願いしております。
As COVID-19 prevention, please wear masks, disinfect hands, and maintain social distancing.
ご観覧頂く際やロビー内でもお客様同士の距離間隔を保っていただくようご協力をお願いいたします。
We ask you to maintain distance between yourselves while viewing and in the lobby.
入場時に検温にて体温確認させていただいておりますが、万が一体調に異変を感じる場合は無理をせず係員へお申し出ください。
We check temperatures at entry, but if you feel unwell, please don't hesitate to notify a staff member.
客席内での模襲、ライブ、ジャンプ等の危険行為、ルールに反したコンサートライトの使用は禁止となります。
Dangerous acts such as crowding, jumping, and rule-violating concert lights are prohibited in seating.
以上のことが守られない場合はコンサートを一時中断もしくは中止させていただきますので、あらかじめご了解ください。
Please note the concert may be paused or canceled if these rules are not followed.
本公演は映像配信および写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り、客席のお客さまの様子が映り込む場合がございます。
Cameras for video streaming and photography will be present, and audience members may appear on camera.
これらの映像や写真はプロモーション等に使用される可能性がございますので、あらかじめご了解ください。
Please be aware these images and footage may be used for promotional purposes.
コンサート終了後は危険防止、また距離確保のため、ブロックごとの呼び出しによる規制退場にご協力のほどよろしくお願いいたします。
After the concert, to prevent danger and ensure distance, we ask for your cooperation in staggered exits by block.
係員の指示があるまでご自身のお席でお待ちください。
Please wait in your seat until instructed by staff.
また、昨日政府より表明がありました通り、イベント会場での声出し収容上限が100%となりましたので、本公演においても声を出して応援が可能です。
Also, as announced by the government yesterday, the vocal capacity limit at event venues is now 100%, so you can cheer with your voice in this performance.
それではまもなく開演いたします。お席に立ってお待ちください。
The performance will begin shortly. Please stay in your seats and wait.
パッと弾けた感情に
With a burst of emotion,
言い訳を並べて過ごした
I spent my time making excuses.
葛藤も知らない街明かり
City lights oblivious to any struggle,
君だけだって嘘をついた
I lied, saying it was only you.
信じたくもないままで踊っている
Dancing without even wanting to believe.
示すために続け, 続けた言葉
Words I kept stringing together to prove it.
見えてるの ぼくの ぼくの この声が 聞こえてる？
Can you see me? Can you hear my voice?
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすらも透明で
even my silhouette is transparent,
きっと不格好だけれど
surely looking quite clumsy, but still
でもせめて声を枯らそう
let me at least strain my voice.
必死に紡いでもずっと証明を ねぇゴーストみたいだ
Desperately hammering away, always proving—hey, I'm like a ghost.
散々怨んだ明るさと
Resenting the brightness so much,
意味ありげに伸びていく影
shadows stretching out so meaningfully.
淡々と過ぎた一粒の
A single drop that passed by indifferently,
君の言葉で泣きたくなった
your words made me want to cry.
大切にしたいものが零れていく
Things I want to cherish are slipping away.
示すままに紡ぎ続けたい言葉
Words I want to keep stringing together as shown.
見えてるの ぼくの ぼくの この声が 届いてる？
Can you see me? Can my voice reach you?
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすらも透明で
even my silhouette is transparent,
きっと不格好だけれど
clumsy, but still
だから叫んで足掻いて
so I scream and struggle.
裸足のままで走って
Running barefoot,
ねぇ気付いて教えてよ 答えは
hey, notice me and tell me the answer.
こんな僕の心まで馬鹿にしないで
Don't mock even a heart like mine.
灰色ームの街が嘲っている
The gray city mocks me.
足取りも重くなる
My footsteps grow heavier.
声を枯らして叫んで足掻いて
Straining my voice, screaming and struggling,
裸足で走り続けて
continuing to run barefoot.
変わらないように 諦めないように
So as not to change, so as not to give up,
ねぇ紡ぐだけだよ
I'll just keep spinning words.
見つけてよ ぼくの ぼくの この声が 聞こえてる？
Find me—can you hear my voice?
Dancer in the dark
シルエットすらも透明で
even my silhouette is transparent,
きっと不格好だけれど
clumsy, but still
でもせめて声を枯らそう
let me at least strain my voice.
必死に紡いでもずっと証明を ねぇゴーストみたいだ
Desperately hammering away, always proving—hey, I'm like a ghost.
退屈な日常を
A boring daily routine
このまま壊してしまえば
if I were to break it right now,
跡形もなくなって歴史になるんだ
it would vanish without a trace and become history.
其処に立つ私に
To me standing there,
Ah
常識とやらなんてものは
Things like conventional wisdom
知らなくていいんだよ
you don't need to know about them.
こっちのベースで争う続くから
Because our battle on this beat continues.
世界中が敵でも
Even if the whole world is against me,
燃えるほど 突っ切るほど
as long as I burn and break through,
ステージは熱くなる
the stage gets hotter.
だからまだ振り絞れよハニー
So strain harder still, honey!
ちゃんと声は届くから
My voice will reach you for sure.
Ah
全れないあいつに
To that irreplaceable someone,
燃やすかいたって
I want to burn it all down,
その家の中だってここを
even inside that house, right here
心臓に
deep in my heart,
どう調子をしてるんだろ
I wonder how it's tuned.
Ah
見出せ勝手に僕として
Find me however you like as myself!
言葉にできなくなった
It became something I could no longer put into words,
歴史になるんだ
becoming history.
そこに立つ私に
To me standing there.
燃え尽きて
Burning out,
灼熱にて
in the scorching heat...
だって僕らは星だから
Because we are stars,
stellar stellar
きっと君はもう気付いていた 僕の心の奥で描いた
I'm sure you had already noticed what I drew deep inside my heart.
それがこれから話す陳腐なモノローグさ
That's the cliché monologue I'm about to tell you.
ずっと言えない言葉があった 壊せない壁があったんだ ずっとさ
There were words I could never say, an unbreakable wall, always.
ふっと香り立つ朝の匂いが どうしようもなく憎々しくて
The sudden scent of morning was hopelessly hateful,
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて震えていた
and I was shaking in the corner of my room hugging my knees.
太陽なんかいらないから 明けないでいて
I don't need the sun, so please don't let the dawn break.
その手を伸ばして 誰かに届くように
Extend that hand, so it reaches someone.
僕だって君と同じ 特別なんかないから
I'm just like you, nothing special at all,
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ
That's right, I sing to the night.
だって僕は星だから stellar stellar
For I'm a star, stellar stellar.
きっと君はもう気づいていた
I'm sure you'd already noticed,
僕の心の奥で描いた
drawn deep within my heart—
それがこれから話す陳腐なモノローグさ
the clichéd monologue I'll now share.
ずっと言えない言葉があった
There were words I could never say,
壊せない壁があったんだ ずっとさ
and walls I could never break down, forever.
ふっと香るたつの朝の匂いが
The sudden scent of morning
どうしようもなく憎々しくて
felt so unbearably hateful,
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて震えていていた
I hugged my knees in the corner of the room, trembling.
太陽なんかいらないから
I don't need the sunshine at all,
明けないでいて
please don't let day break.
その手を伸ばして誰かに届くように
Extend your hand so it reaches someone,
僕だって君と同じ 特別なんかじゃないから
for I'm just like you, nothing special at all.
そうさ僕は夜を歌う stellar stellar
Yes, I sing to the night, stellar stellar,
ありったけの輝きで 今宵音楽は鳴り止まない
shining with all I've got, the music won't stop tonight.
そうだ僕がずっとなりたかったのは
Yes, what I always wanted to be
待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ
wasn't a waiting Cinderella,
迎えに行く王子様だ
but the prince going to rescue her.
だって僕は星だから stellar stellar
For I'm a star, stellar stellar.
きっと君はもう気づいていた
I'm sure you had already noticed
僕の心の奥で描いた
that script drawn deep within my heart,
それがこれから話す陳腐なモノローグさ
which is the clichéd monologue I'll now tell you.
ずっと言えない言葉があった
There were words I could never say,
壊せない壁があったんだ ずっとさ
and walls I could never break down, forever.
ふっと香るたつの朝の匂いが
The sudden scent of morning
どうしようもなく憎々しくて
felt so unbearably hateful,
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて震えていていた
I hugged my knees in the corner of the room, trembling.
太陽なんかいらないから
I don't need the sunshine at all,
明けないでいて
please don't let day break.
その手を伸ばして誰かに届くように
Extend your hand so it reaches someone,
僕だって君と同じ 特別なんかじゃないから
for I'm just like you, nothing special at all.
そうさ僕は夜を歌う stellar stellar
Yes, I sing to the night, stellar stellar,
ありったけの輝きで 今宵音楽は鳴り止まない
shining with all I've got, the music won't stop tonight.
おとぎ話みたいなら
If it's like a fairy tale,
おとぎ話みたいな
like a fairy tale...
だって僕は星だから stellar stellar
For I'm a star, stellar stellar,
きっと君はもう気づいていた
I'm sure you had already noticed
僕の心の奥で描いた
that script drawn deep within my heart,
それがこれから話す陳腐なモノローグさ
which is the clichéd monologue I'll now tell you.
ずっと言えない言葉があった
There were words I could never say,
壊せない壁があったんだ ずっとさ
and walls I could never break down, forever.
ふっと香るたつの朝の匂いが
The sudden scent of morning
どうしようもなく憎々しくて
felt so unbearably hateful,
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて震えていていた
I hugged my knees in the corner of the room, trembling.
太陽なんかいらないから
I don't need the sunshine at all,
明けないでいて
please don't let day break.
その手を伸ばして誰かに届くように
Extend your hand so it reaches someone,
僕だって君と同じ 特別なんかじゃないから
for I'm just like you, nothing special at all.
そうさ僕は夜を歌う stellar stellar
Yes, I sing to the night, stellar stellar,
ありったけの輝きで 今宵音楽は鳴り止まない
shining with all I've got, the music won't stop tonight.
ステラ ステラ ああ
Stellar, stellar, ah...
熱くなる準備できてますか
Are you ready to get fired up?
いつもより上げろ！
Turn it up even higher!
画面の向こうもそのまた向こうで
Even beyond the screen, further out there,
放たれた言葉たち 殴っても痛まない冷酷な拳
the words unleashed are ruthless fists.
満点の星のように散らばっている
Scattered like a sky full of stars,
カラスの羽の上を裸足で歩ような痛みだ
it feels like walking barefoot over crow feathers.
僕はずっと苦しかったんだ
I've been suffering all this time.
そんな国にとって正気なんてどうだっていい
To such a country, sanity doesn't matter at all.
この線が確かな違いだって自分で決めたんだ
I decided for myself that this line is the true difference.
鏡に映った僕の色は全部
All the colors of me reflected in the mirror
自分のためにやったのに
were done for my own sake.
鏡の上に映った
Reflected on the mirror surface,
僕の色は全部
all my colors...
僕のためにやったのに気づいたらこの手を離れていた
were done for my own sake, yet before I knew it, my hands let go.
名前も顔も隠した
Hiding both my name and my face.
つまらないデイイズもう散々ね！
Boring days are already over!
奇蹟願っているだけの人生
A life where you're just wishing for miracles
watch me do…
Watch me do...
呪術秘中トリック無しのマジック
Magic without any tricks or secrets
I wanna be free! だってまだふりだし
I wanna be free! 'Cause I'm still at the starting line
(The party ain't started)
heyタクシーちょっと宇宙迄
Hey taxi, take me to space for a bit
秒針は音を立てて夜を急かす魔霊のように
The second hand ticks loudly, urging the night like a monster
人生は一瞬にして溶ける魔法
Life is magic that melts away in an instant
それならば駆け抜け手際想い通り！
If that's the case, run through it just as you wish!
お召しな馬車飛び乗ってdrivin' あたしは大変身メイクアップ！
Jump on the carriage and start drivin', I'm getting a complete makeover!
我儘のままに爛爛に輝きに注意
Watch out for the selfish brilliance
洒落た街でdancin' 左様なら劣等感
Dancing in a stylish town, goodbye inferiority complex
何時かは喝采クラップオウデエンス 諸々御詠唱あれ！
Someday, an audience applause, everyone join in chanting!
bibbidi bobbidi boowa 混濁がっても仕様がない
Bibbidi bobbidi boowa, even if it's chaotic there's no helping it
ガラス シューズで踊る tonight
Dancing in glass shoes tonight
bibbidi bobbidi boowa 今夜に明日などない
Bibbidi bobbidi boowa, there's no tomorrow tonight
ならば自由に踊った者勝ちでしょぅ？
So those who dance freely win, right?
dance! ラララリホ どんな問題も解は一つ
Dance! La la la li ho, every problem has a single solution
白紙も正解も間違いも愛す本的あたしの理想
Loving blank papers, correct answers, and mistakes—my true ideal
何だか世界は限界の気味がして
Somehow the world feels like it's reaching its limit
ただただ安心じゃあ心配
Just being safe is worrying
今すぐ jumpin out
Jumpin' out right now!
chitty chitty bang bang chitty bang bang
唯々諾々に危機感抱く日々にぎりぎり爆発気味
Feeling a crisis in docile days, on the verge of explosion
たった今発散してしまおうかまだまだビイビイ弾巧みに乱射
Shall we let loose right now? Still skillfully spraying bb bullets
一発じゃあ撃ち足りないわ ついに導き出した君にアンサー
One shot isn't enough; finally I found the answer for you
灰になる迄踊って居よぅ
Let's dance until we turn to ash
お召しな馬車飛び乗ってdrivin' あたしは大変身メイクアップ！
Jump on the carriage and start drivin', I'm getting a complete makeover!
我儘のままに爛爛に輝きに注意
Watch out for the selfish brilliance
洒落た街でdancin' 左様なら劣等感
Dancing in a stylish town, goodbye inferiority complex
何時かは喝采クラップオウデエンス 諸々御詠唱あれ！
Someday, an audience applause, everyone join in chanting!
bibbidi bobbidi boowa 混濁がっても仕様がない
Bibbidi bobbidi boowa, even if it's chaotic there's no helping it
ガラス シューズで踊る tonight
Dancing in glass shoes tonight
bibbidi bobbidi boowa 今夜に明日などない
Bibbidi bobbidi boowa, there's no tomorrow tonight
ならば自由に踊った者勝ちでしょぅ？
So those who dance freely win, right?
dance! ラララリホ どんな問題も解は一つ
Dance! La la la li ho, every problem has a single solution
白紙も正解も間違いも愛す本的あたしの理想
Loving blank papers, correct answers, and mistakes—my true ideal
何だか世界は限界の気味がして
Somehow the world feels like it's reaching its limit
ただただ安心じゃあ心配
Just being safe is worrying
今すぐ jumpin out
Jumpin' out right now!
chitty chitty bang bang chitty bang bang
唯々諾々に危機感抱く日々にぎりぎり爆発気味
Feeling a crisis in docile days, on the verge of explosion
たった今発散してしまおうかまだまだビイビイ弾巧みに乱射
Shall we let loose right now? Still skillfully spraying bb bullets
一発じゃあ撃ち足りないわ ついに導き出した君にアンサー
One shot isn't enough; finally I found the answer for you
灰になる迄踊って居よぅ
Let's dance until we turn to ash
君も君も巡ってる復習も全部信じ得てあげる
You too, you too, I'll believe all your recurring revenges
無茶じゃないのだってあなたとほら
It's not unreasonable, because look, with you...
ツルルルルルル 弧線描くんだって間違って
Drawing an arc, even if we make mistakes
嘘じゃない
It's no lie
あれもこれも追いすがるジャージ
Chasing after jerseys and everything else
水星のこと現れたさの現役
The active status of Hoshimachi's appearance
アイウォントヴイツーの星屑彗星でスイチョワ
Suichowa with stardust Suisei of I want V2
今日もかわいい完璧の準備終わり過ぎ
Today too, cute, perfection preparation is way too done
乗り込む君はラジラジが
You stepping in, radi-radi-ga
人間人びと人びと人びと人びと おやっやおやっ なんでこれは随分噛み砕け
People, people, people, people... Oh my, oh my, why is this so well-chewed?
又新しい青春駆使情緒系
A new youth-utilizing emotional type
こんな場所で終わらせない全力投球よ
I won't end it in a place like this, going all out!
君も君も巡ってる復習も全部
You too, you too, all your recurring revenges
辰巳真澄でだいぶ信じてあげる
I'll believe you quite a bit in Tatsumi Masumi
無茶じゃないのだってあなたとほら
It's not unreasonable, because look, with you...
ツルルルルルル 弧線描くんだってただ星と歌う
Drawing an arc, just singing with the stars
嘘じゃない 幾度もめてリベンジがしょう
It's not a lie, no matter how many times we argue and get revenge
あれもこれも
This and that too
おいしゅうございますすいちゃん
It's delicious, Suichan!
流用何万回と生せ生き様急生
Reusing tens of thousands of times, live your life abruptly
入るべき場所 意義 意味 存分存分みんな探してる
Everyone is fully searching for the place, meaning, and significance they belong
手の平に答えがなくば文句も言えない
If there's no answer in the palm of your hand, you can't even complain
旅立ちをたまに 旅立ちをたまに…
Setting off occasionally, setting off occasionally...
分身だって 分身情も生み出してあげる
I'll even create clones and clone-emotions for you,
寂しくないよ だってあなたもほら
You're not lonely, because you see, you too...
すり抜けてく チョコゼリー論理だって惑う
Slipping through, even chocolate-jelly logic gets confused,
ウソじゃないの だってあなたもほら
It's no lie, because you see, you too...
すり抜けてく 分身情を抱きしめてあげる
I'll hold and embrace the clone-emotions slipping through,
寂しくないよ だってあなたもほら
You're not lonely, because you see, you too...
僕が先導してただ星と歌う
I'll take the lead and just sing with the stars.
すぐじゃない
Not right away—
受け止めれたら おいしゅーございます
once I successfully catch it, bon appétit!
Oh it's you, 'cause you're...
えー、星街すいせい セカンドライブ
Um, Hoshimachi Suisei's 2nd Live,
Shuto in Crisisに ご来場ありがとうございます！
"Shuto in Crisis," thank you all so much for coming!
ふう、やばい、ここで飛び跳ねると後半の体力があれじゃちゃうので落ち着きますけど
Phew, yikes, if I jump around here my stamina for the second half will drain, so I'll calm down, but...
皆さん、なんと今日は声が出せるんですよね！
Everyone, amazingly, you can use your voices today!
うわー、久しぶりすぎるこの感覚。もうね、今日も可愛いって言ってもらえてめちゃめちゃ気持ちよかったです。ありがとうございます。
Wow, this feeling is way too nostalgic. I felt so amazing hearing you all say I'm cute today. Thank you so much.
いやあもうファーストに比べてもうセカンドはとんでもなくでかい会場になりまして、えー、5回まであるそうです。
Man, compared to the first [live], the second one is in such an insanely huge venue, and uh, there are up to five screenings apparently.
5回目のみなさん、4回目のみなさん、3回目のみなさん、2回目のみなさん、アリーナ！いぇーい！
To everyone at the 5th, 4th, 3rd, 2nd, and the Arena! Yay!
はい、えー、つい先日発売したニューアルバム『Specter』はみんな聴いてくれましたか？
Right, um, has everyone listened to my new album "Specter" that was released just the other day?
え、なんと今回は素敵なバンドメンバーの名前そうで、その曲たちを披露したいと思います！
And amazingly, this time, introducing the amazing band members by name, I'd like to showcase those songs!
はい、えー配信で見てるみんなのコメントも見えてます。ここ、ここがねなんか配信用のカメラらしくて、おーい、いぇーい。ちょ、会場のみんなも多分見えてる。見えてるよね？わーい！いぇーい、生バンドすげえってコメントも
Right, um, I can also see the comments from everyone watching via stream. Here, this is apparently the streaming camera—hey, yay! Hey, everyone at the venue can probably see too. You can see, right? Yay! Yay! There are even comments like "live band is amazing"...
なんとなしにちょっと宙に浮いてるコメント読めるんだけど。パチパチありがとう。
I can read comments floating in mid-air somewhat. Thank you for the applause.
はい、すいちゃんと目が合うこのカメラあのたびたび抜いてもらえますんでこれぜひね注目してください。
Right, this camera where you make eye contact with Suichan gets cut to repeatedly, so please definitely pay attention to it.
今日可愛い！
"You're cute today!"
あ、そうだ、いつもの挨拶ね、なんか曲中でしかやってなかったからやったほうがいいですよね！
Oh right, my usual greeting, you know, I only ever did it during songs, so I should totally do it, right?
すいちゃ、行きますよ！ すいちゃのこと変えられた明日への原石アイドルVtuberの星街すいせいです！ すいちゃんはーー！
Suicha, here we go! The raw gemstone of tomorrow who snatched Suicha's heart, VTuber Hoshimachi Suisei! Suichan is—!
最高ー！ 声出し最高ー！
The best! Vocalizing is the best!
うわあ、もうね、無理だと思いましたよ声を出すのは。なんとかもう今日になって、あの会場に着いてから運営さんに「すいせさん、ビッグニュースがあります。声出しオッケーです」って言われて、やった！やった！うれしいみんなもね存分に声出してください。お隣さんにね気を使ってねあの楽しんでくださいね。
Man, I thought it was impossible to use our voices. Somehow, today, after arriving at the venue, management told me, "Suisei-san, big news. Voice cheering is okay." Yay! Yay! I'm so happy, everyone please voice your hearts out to your heart's content. Just be considerate of the person next to you and have fun, okay?
えー、#キラキラ星街で今日のライブはツイートしてほしいです。あの配信の皆さんとかね。お願いします。トレンドに入ってるんじゃないかな？今、今、ない？今ない？おっ、なんかライブ始まる前にね1位になって、ありがとうございます。やった！うれしい！
Um, I'd like you to tweet about today's live with the hashtag #SparklingHoshimachi. To everyone watching the stream, too, please. It might be trending, right? Right now, right now—not right now? Oh, somehow before the live started it became #1, thank you so much. Yay! I'm so happy!
はい、えーではでは、えーYouTubeとTikTokで見てるみんなはここでお別れになってしまうので、ぜひぜひ配信チケットを買って続きをご観覧ください。君たち見れるでしょ？君たちは見れるでしょ？はい、なんか今回は初めてあのTikTokで
Right, um, well then, everyone watching on YouTube and TikTok will be parting ways here, so please definitely buy a streaming ticket to watch the rest. You guys can see it, right? You guys can see it, right? Yeah, somehow this time, for the first time on TikTok...
配信もやってるらしくてね
Apparently she's also streaming,
もうこれはZ世代の あの 男女にめちゃめちゃ注目されるんじゃないか
so I think this will get a ton of attention from Gen Z guys and girls.
バズりたい。バズりたいせいちゃん
I wanna go viral. I wanna go viral, Sei-chan.
TikTokでバズりたい。
I wanna go viral on TikTok.
はい、じゃあ買ってくださいね。買って？
So, please buy it, okay? Will you?
では、今日はいつものアイドルVTuber星街すいせいとはちょっと一味違う私をお見せできればと思います。
Today, I hope to show you a side of me a bit different from your usual idol VTuber, Hoshimachi Suisei.
会場のみんなも配信のみんなも まだまだ盛り上がる準備できてますか？
Are you all at the venue and streaming ready to get even more hyped up?
それでは聴いてください。「灼熱にて純情」
Now then, please listen to "Shakunetsu nite Junjou".
無料パートは終了いたしました。ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The free portion has ended. Thank you for watching!
無料パートは終了いたしました ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The free part has ended. Thank you for watching!